linaro.org 2011-12-09

# Data use and privacy policy

We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of users of web sites operated by or on behalf of Linaro™  Limited (together " **Linaro Website** "). This statement explains how We collect, use and safeguard Data (defined below) you provide when using a Linaro Website.  This statement forms part of and is incorporated into the [Terms and Conditions of Use](http://www.linaro.org/terms/). Any personal information which may be collected from an Linaro Website will be treated in accordance with this privacy policy, the Data Protection Act 1998, as amended and other applicable laws.  For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998, the data controller is Linaro Limited, a company registered in England and Wales with company number 07180318 (hereinafter "We/Us/Our").  Registered office address: Lockton House, Clarendon Rd, Cambridge. CB2 8FH., United Kingdom.  Linaro Limited is a private limited company.

By using an Linaro Website, you consent to the collection and use of your information in the manner and for the purposes set out below.

### What personal information is collected?

When you send Us an email or visit an Linaro Website, We may collect, from both public and private areas of the Linaro Website, personal information volunteered by you about you, including name, title, company, county, mailing address, email address, phone numbers, fax numbers, age range and company size and Our web server logs, browser cookies and local shared objects may collect details of your domain name, operating system, browser type, IP address and a unique identifier for your computer, or other access device (" **Data** ").  When you submit Data you are agreeing to its transfer, storage and processing.

### Who is collecting the Data?

When you are on a Linaro Website and are asked for Data, you are sharing that Data with Linaro Limited and its related companies.  The Data may be stored in the European Economic Area ("EEA") or transferred to and stored at a destination outside the EEA.  Data may be disclosed to and processed by staff operating outside of the EEA who work for Us and Our related companies.

The Linaro Website may also contain various links to third-party web sites. Third-party web sites may provide additional information, goods, services and/or promotions. These sites are owned and operated independently from Us, and have their own separate privacy and data collection practices. Any Data you provide to these web sites will be governed under the terms of their privacy policy, if any. We have no responsibility or liability whatsoever for the independent actions or policies of these independent sites, and are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such sites.

### How is your Data used?

Data maybe used internally by Us, including updating Our databases, contacting you with requested information, maintaining a technical support history, sending marketing information, determining trends in your use of Our product, aiding in the design of Our product and services, processing your enquiries, measuring the use of Our sites, administering and improving the content of Our sites.

### With whom do We share your Data?

Except as expressly stated in this policy or on Our web sites, We do not provide your Data to third parties without your consent.

If you register and provide information to a forum or blog the information you provide will be published for anyone to see.

We may occasionally share aggregated demographic Data with Our partners. This Data is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

We process data in the ordinary course of business and We use third parties to provide services on Our behalf.   We will provide your relevant Data to them solely for the purposes of the effective delivery of such services.

In the event that We sell or buy any business or assets, or if Linaro or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party the relevant Data held by Us will be one of the transferred assets.

We may use your Data if We are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply Our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Linaro, Our customers, or others. 

### What choices do you have regarding the collection, use and distribution of your Data?

We may, from time to time, send you email or direct mail regarding Our products and services. If you do not want to receive such information, simply tell Us when you give Us your Data, or follow the directions contained on the mailing to remove your name from Our mailing list(s).

You also have the right to access (review, correct, amend or delete) your Data by contacting Us. Individuals are responsible for providing Linaro with accurate and complete personal information, and for contacting Us if correction of such information is required. Please note that, where permitted, We may charge a nominal fee for fulfilling access requests and that to the extent permitted by Law We reserve the right to disallow unreasonable requests for access.

Please direct any questions concerning Linaro's privacy practices or if you have any queries or requests in relation to your Data to [privacy@linaro.org](mailto:privacy@linaro.org) or Linaro Limited, 110 Fulbourn Road, Cambridge, CB1 9NJ, United Kingdom. Requests to unsubscribe from ("opt-out") of communications from Linaro may also be sent to unsubscribe at [privacy@linaro.org](mailto:privacy@linaro.org).

### How secure is your Data?

We always use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving Data. We have appropriate security measures in place to protect against any loss, misuse or alteration of information that We have collected.  However, We cannot ensure or otherwise warrant the security of any information you provide to Us or from an Linaro Website, and therefore you use the Linaro Website at your own risk.

### What about browser cookies and local shared objects?

We may collect and store information about your visit to Our web site automatically using browser cookies (files which are sent by Us to your computer) or similar devices which We can access when you visit Our web site in future.   We may also use local shared objects, sometimes known as Adobe Flash cookies, to remember settings, preferences and usage similar to browser cookies.

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google").  Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage.  Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google.  You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.  By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

If you want to stop browser cookies being stored on your computer in future or if you want to delete any browser cookies that are already on your computer, please refer to your browser manufacturer's instructions by clicking "Help" in your browser menu. Information on deleting or controlling browser cookies is available at http://www.AboutCookies.org. If you want to control or prevent local shared objects being stored on your computer, please refer to Adobe's website directly (<http://www.adobe.com/products/flashplayer/security/>).  Please note that by deleting or disabling browser cookies or local shared objects you may not be able to use certain areas or features of Our site.

### Changes to this privacy policy

We may revise this privacy policy at any time by amending this page. You are expected to check this page from time to time to take notice of any changes We made, as they are binding on you. Some of the provisions contained in this privacy policy may also be superseded by provisions or notices published elsewhere on Our site.

Thank you for visiting Our site.

LEC-ELA-00990-V2.0, 27 April, 2010, Copyright (c) 2010 Linaro Limited
